Guide to the Wanted Posters Collection, 1914-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Wanted Posters collection 1914-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
3.0 Linear Feet 2350 Items
Miscellaneous posters collected by Westchester County, New York precinct.
Posters of wanted criminals collected by an unknown police detective in Westchester County, New York. Posters are from the United States and Canada. Collection includes some well-known criminals such as Lester Gillis, alias Baby Face Nelson; Mary Evelyn Frechette, alias Mrs. John Dillinger; Arthur “Doc” Barker; mobster Roger Touhy; and bank robber Frank Nash. Radicals from 1970s include Weather Underground member Cathlyn Platt Wilkerson, Symbionese Liberation Army member Kathleen Soliah; and Black Liberation Army fugitives JoAnne Chesimard (Assata Shakur) and brother Mutulu Shakur.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Wanted Posters Collection were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2013.
Historical Note
These posters were collected by an anonymous detective of the Westcheser County, NY police department.
Collection Overview
This collection consists of posters of wanted criminals collected by an anonymous police detective in Westchester County, NY during the 20th century. Posters are from the United States and Canada. The bulk of the collection is from the Federal Bureau of Investigation in Washington, D.C. The collection includes some well-known criminals such as Lester Gillis, alias Baby Face Nelson; Mary Evelyn Frechette, alias Mrs. John Dillinger; Arthur "Doc" Barker; mobster Roger Touhy; and bank robber Frank Nash. Radicals from the 1970s include Weather Underground member Cathlyn Platt Wilkerson; Symbionese Liberation Army member Kathleen Soliah; and Black Liberation Army fugitives JoAnne Chesimard (Assata Shakur) and her brother, Mutulu Shakur.
The collection includes approximately 2,250 small-format wanted posters, most measuring 8 x 8 inches. Posters range in size and condition, many with manuscript markings or inked stamps, and some are trimmed and pasted onto printed mug shot cards. The collection was first arranged geographically, then further divided chronologically. Well-known criminals aforementioned are located in their indicated folders. Posters from the Federal Bureau of Investigation are included in the folders marked "District of Columbia." Folders are alphabetized in each box, with the exception of the District of Columbia, which occupies Box 2 entirely.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Shakur, Assata
Shakur, Mutulu
Barker, Arthur
Soliah, Kathleen
Nelson, Baby Face
Nash, Frank
Frechette, Mary Evelyn
Touhy, Roger
United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
Weather Underground Organization
United States. Westchester County (N.Y.)
Criminals -- United States
Wanted posters -- United States
Wanted posters -- Canada
Contents of Collection
- Wanted Posters, 1914-1988, (2 boxes)
  - Alabama, 1922-1930 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas, 1921 (Box 1)
  - California, 1915-1933 (Box 1)
  - Canada, 1924-1929 (Box 1)
  - Colorado, 1924-1950 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut, 1920-1930 (Box 1)
  - Georgia, 1925-1954 (Box 1)
  - Idaho, 1927-1931 (Box 1)
  - Illinois, 1924-1956 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Indiana, 1915 (Box 1)
  - Iowa, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - Kansas, 1910s-1950s, 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes Frank Nash.
  - Kentucky, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Massachusetts, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, 1919-1950s and undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Minnesota, 1919-1967 (Box 1)
  - Missouri, 1923-1969 (Box 1)
  - Montana, 1929 (Box 1)
  - Nebraska, 1929 (Box 1)
  - New Hampshire, 1929 (Box 1)
  - New Jersey, 1921-1939 and undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - New York, 1910s-1950s, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - New York, undated (Box 3)
  - Nevada, 1918 (Box 1)
  - North Dakota, 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - Ohio, 1915-1951 (Box 1)
  - Oklahoma, 1923-1924 (Box 1)
  - Oregon, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Pennsylvania, 1920s-1950s, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Rhode Island, 1934 (Box 1)
  - South Carolina, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Tennessee, 1926-1934 (Box 1)
  - Texas, 1923-1949 (Box 1)
  - Virginia, 1924-1932 (Box 1)
  - Washington, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Wisconsin, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Wyoming, 1920-1937 (Box 1)
  - Unknown Location (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - District of Columbia, 1915-1929, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - District of Columbia, 1930-1934 (Box 2)
    Includes Mary Evelyn Frechette, alias Mrs. John Dillinger; Lester Gillis, alias Baby Face Nelson; and Arthur "Doc" Barker.
  - District of Columbia, 1935-1939, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - District of Columbia, 1940-1944, 2 folders (Box 2)
    Includes Roger Touhy.
  - District of Columbia, 1945-1959, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - District of Columbia, 1960s-1980s (Box 3)
    Includes JoAnne Chesimard (Assata Shakur); Mutulu Shakur; Kathleen Ann Soliah; and Kathlyn Platt Wilkerson.
  - District of Columbia, undated (Box 3)